本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：yank121    zlean    soda    Silmar    花零落
翻译：meredith49     时间轴：Angelica     特效：Will
■
校对：凤姐      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
嘿  伙计们
Hi, guys.
绝
命
毒
师
第三季
第十二集
如果可以的话
So if it's okay,
我想开这辆车去考驾照
I was thinking about using this one for the test.
老妈的车的刹车太难搞了
Mom's brakes are very sticky--
你轻轻踩一下
and you barely press down on them,
就会有尖锐的刹车声
and it's like a screech.
当然可以
Sure.
我开的还可以吗
But I'm good?
是的  你开得不错
Yeah, you're great.
怎么了
Why?
我的脚没关系吗
Um, are my feet okay?
-哦  -我查过了
- Ah. - I looked it up.
新墨西哥州规定说
New Mexico says
我只需开个医生证明就行了
all I need is a note from a doctor.
我知道这根本不是什么正道
I mean, I know it's not the right way and all,
可是一旦我有了临时执照
but once I get my provisional,
我就能一直用下去
I can keep working at it.
只要你能注意行车安全
Well, as long as it gets you safely from point A to point B,
那我干嘛要反对呢
then who am I to argue?
洗钱  维基百科  免费的百科全书
Money laundering. From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia.
嗨
Hi.
你是个可爱的小女孩  你真可爱
You're a sweet girl. Yes, you are.
洗钱的现代发展史
你真可爱哦  太可爱了
Yes, you are. Yes, you are.
我知道了
I know.
资金的提供
我知道了
I know.
-给你双拐  -给你钥匙
- There you go. - Here you go.
好的
All right.
谢谢
Thank you.
-好了吗  -是的
- Got it? - Yeah.
好  好了
Okay. All right.
是周六早上9点考吗
So 9 A.M. Saturday?
周六早上9点
9 A.M. Saturday.
那你8点半来接我
So, which means pick me up about 8:30.
我会满怀热情的出现在这里的
I'll be here with bells on.
什么
What?
我就这么一说
Just a saying.
别担心  我不会穿着喇叭裤来的
Don't worry. I won't be wearing bells.
-嘿  -嘿  妈
- Hey. - Hey, Mom.
-你有时间吗  -有
- Hi. Um, do you have a minute? - Yeah.
你能进去替我照看一下你妹妹吗
Could you go in and keep an eye on your sister for me?
好的  当然可以
Yeah, sure.
-谢谢  -很好  -再见  老爸
- Thanks. - All right. - See you, Dad.
再见  儿子  对了  今天表现不错
Bye, son. Hey, good work today.
谢谢
Thank you.
你有再想过我们讨论的事情吗
Have you thought anymore about what we discussed?
"再想过"  意思是重新考虑吗
"Thought any more," Meaning reconsidered?
没有
No.
那你就告诉我哪个地方不行
So show me the flaw in it.
是"很多个地方"  斯凯勒
Uh, "Flaws," Skyler.
"很多地方"  是复数  不是单数
"Flaws," plural, not singular.
你要我从何说起呢
Where do you want me to start?
我很讨厌现在的状况  好吗
Hey, I don't love this situation, all right,
是你拖我下水的
that you put me in.
不管怎样  我们还是接着说点有用的吧
However, let's just stick with what makes sense here.
你拿了本钱  去赌博
You took the seed money. You went gambling.
然后把钱投到了洗车生意上
You invested it in the car wash
经营了四年的时间
that you helped run for four years.
你雇了你老婆来做会计
You hired your wife as a bookkeeper.
你猜为什么  因为她真是个会计
Because guess what? She's actually a bookkeeper.
这才是审计员会相信的故事
Now, that is a story an auditor can believe,
我有漏掉些什么吗
so what am I missing?
你漏掉了这种选择
You're missing
那就是  你只是接受了我给你的这笔钱
that you should just take this money that I give you
但并没有仔细查看过有多少
and not look too closely at it,
因为如果哪天我被抓了  但愿不会
so if, God forbid, I get caught,
你依然能洗脱嫌疑
you maintain plausible deniability.
那照你这说法  你我关系不和
Okay, my estranged husband
在你还在工作那会儿
who, when he was working,
每年能挣43000美元
made $43,000 a year,
然后突然你开始把所有钱都给我
starts shoveling money at me,
然后你指望警察找我的时候
and when the police come,
我这样说吗
I'm supposed to say,
"天啊  我从没仔细想过  警官
"Gee, I never thought about it, officers.
我当时并没觉得有什么不对劲"
Made sense to me."
你真觉得我能靠这样洗脱嫌疑吗
Really? That, in your mind, is plausible deniability?
我直说了吧  沃尔特
I'll tell you what, Walt.
我倒宁愿他们把我
I'd rather have them
当成那个叫什么邦妮的女人
think I'm Bonnie what's-her-name
电影《雌雄大盗》里的女主角  女骗子
而不是一个十足的傻瓜
than some complete idiot.
那你这是在提出警告了
So you're promoting caution here.
想要一个可信的故事
And you want a believable story.
在我看来
That, it seems to me,
那才是应付目前最为稳妥的办法
is the safest way to make the best out of a very bad situation,
就是这样
yes.
不过我在你的故事里发现了一个小漏洞
But I'm noting a little hole in your plot, though.
既然你丈夫与你不和
Why would your estranged husband
那他为什么要为你做这些事呢
be doing all this for you?
因为他爱他的家庭
Because he loves his family
而且非常想要和解
and desperately wants a reconciliation,
虽然绝不可能
though it may be hopeless and futile.
但他却愿意为此付出一切努力
Then again, he'd try anything.
恕我无法相信
I'm just not buying it.
我觉得如果夫妻之间关系有所改善的话
No, I think it would be better
故事会更有说服力
if the husband were no longer estranged.
你知道
You know,
如果他能睡回到他的床上去的话
maybe if he were back sleeping in his own bed.
哇哦
Wow.
你在做白日梦吗
It's suddenly a fantasy story.
我至少得成为这家人的一部分
I am at least going to be a part of this household.
我要每天与家人一起晚餐
Dinner with the family every night of the week.
不能每晚都来  不可能
Not every night, no.
一周六顿晚餐  你有一个晚上的空闲
Six nights a week. You'll get one night off.
两顿晚餐  不能在周末
Dinner two nights, not weekends,
提前一天通知
with 24-hours' notice.
一周五顿晚餐  不需要提前通知
Five nights a week with no notice.
三顿  提前六小时通知
Three, six-hours' notice.
五顿晚餐  提前两小时通知
Five nights a week with two hours' notice.
四顿
Four. F--
你给我适可而止
Don't push it.
我要房子的钥匙
And I want my own key to the house.
没必要
No.
以防急用还有面子问题  所以当然有必要
For emergencies and appearances, yes.
我得照看女儿
I am going to babysit my own daughter.
督促儿子做作业
I'm going to help my son with his homework.
我是家庭的一份子
I am going to be a part of this family,
只有这样  你编的这故事才有说服力
and that is how we'll sell your little fiction.
休息一下  出去喝一杯怎么样
How about we stop somewhere afterward and get a beer?
谢了  不用了
Uh, no. Thanks, though.
改天吧
Maybe some other time.
我认真的  跟我喝一杯
No, seriously. Get a beer with me.
说吧
What?
你搞什么
What the hell are you doing?
是我们的货  对吧
That's ours, right?
好好看看  是我们的吗
Look at it and tell me if that's ours.
没错  给我收起来
Yes, it's ours. Now put it away.
你哪根筋没对
What the hell is wrong with you?
你怎么弄到的  从实验室偷出来的吗
Where did you get that? Did you take it from the lab?
从杀死康宝的那两个人手上买的
I bought it from the two guys who killed Combo.
他们让康宝曝尸街头
They had Combo shot down in the street,
现在又来卖我们的东西
and now it's our product they're selling.
说明他们为我们的人做事
Which means they work for our guy. Right?
什么东西  道听途说
What is that? That's hearsay.
你有证据吗
Do you have any proof?
我从开枪的那小孩的姐姐那里听来的
I heard it from the sister of the kid who shot him.
听见我说"小孩"了吗
Hear how I just said "Kid"?
这小孩
This kid--
才11岁
he's 11 years old--
他们命令他杀死康宝
shot Combo on orders.
这两个卑鄙小人逼他贩毒
These two scumbags, they got him dealing.
他们逼他...
They got him--
你知道这不是头一回了
And you know he's not the first.
他们利用小孩  凭什么不利用
They use kids 'cause, hey, why not?
因为小孩容易控制  容易哄骗
Easy to control, easy to fool.
就算被抓也顶多算少年犯
All they get is juvie if they ever get caught.
笼络人心
Hearts and minds, right?
从小孩抓起  长大后他们就将永远听命于你
Get them young, and they're yours forever.
是他们杀了康宝
These guys killed Combo.
这小孩只是个傀儡
They used this little kid like some puppet.
他们利用他杀了我朋友
They used him to shoot my friend.
为什么要告诉我这些
So why are you telling me this?
我需要你帮忙
I need your help.
怎么帮
How?
我需要蓖麻毒素
I need ricin.
上帝
Oh, my God.
天啊
Oh, God.
那两个  听着
These two-- Hey.
-不行  -听我说
- No. - Hey.
他们必须死
They got to go. All right?
-我计划都想好了  -不行
- I've got the entire thing figured out-- - No.
投毒的方式  一切尽在掌控中
...a delivery method, everything.
我只需要你帮我弄点毒药
All I need from you is the poison, that's all.
-不行  -听我说
- No-- - L-Look,
另外  你不必...
otherwise, you don't have to--
-不行  -你大可袖手旁观
- No-- - ... you don't have to lift a finger.
你根本不知道自己在说什么
Listen, you don't even know what you're talking about.
-这根本  -杀了他们简直是大快人心
- This is not even-- - Look, you don't get how right this is?
你不明白
Huh? You don't get how
整个世界没了他们会更加...
the whole entire world would be better off--
我们不要再谈论这事了
No, we're not even talking about this.
我认识个女的
I know a woman
每周从他们那里买一到两次货
who buys from the these two once or twice a week.
她给他们买汉堡
All right? She brings them hamburgers
因为他们成天在车子里会饿
'cause they sit in their car all day, and they get hungry,
她就带吃的过去
so she brings them food,
作为回报  他们就给她点优惠
and they knock a few bucks off her price.
我们就从这渠道下毒
There's your delivery system right there.
我可以在一英里外等着
I can be a mile away.
老天  干这事  你居然信一个瘾君子
Jesus. A meth-head you're trusting to do this?
你知道个屁  你连襟都搞不定她
You know what? That meth-head stood up to your brother-in-law.
他盘问了她5小时
All right? He questioned her for five hours.
她都没走露半点消息
She didn't give it up.
要证明吗
You know how it is you know it?
你现在没进监狱就是最好的证明
Because you're not in prison right now.
要是我这次答应了  我就该进监狱了
Yeah, well, I know I would be in prison after this.
或者更糟  搞不好把我们都搭进去
Prison or worse, and I'd be right alongside you.
所以不行  杰西  这简直是开国际玩笑
No-- Jesse, you cannot be serious.
这太荒唐了
Listen, this is a ridiculous idea.
荒唐吗
It's ridiculous?
你意思是不可行  是吗
What, so you're saying it's not going to work?
那当时你为什么用这办法
How about back when it was your plan?
为什么当时用这办法来对付屠库
Back when you were going to use it on Tuco?
两码事
Apples and oranges.
一旦中了蓖麻毒
Guy eats ricin.
两三天后  会得流感
Two or three days later, he gets the flu
或者心脏病发作之类  然后就死了
or a heart attack or something, and he keels over.
这可是你说的
That's what you said.
根本查不到我们
Untraceable back to us.
我是说根本查不到我
To-- To me.
连我们上头那混蛋
Not even that other scumbag we work for
也肯定弄不明白怎么回事
is ever going to figure it out.
当时用在屠库身上就是条妙计
Yo, it was a good plan back when it was Tuco,
现在同样也是
and it's a good plan now.
屠库当时想杀我们
Tuco wanted to murder us.
而他们没有
These guys don't.
两码事
Apples and oranges.
需要我坐在这里
Do I really have to sit here
跟你解释个中差异吗
and explain the difference to you?
康宝是我们的人
Combo was us, man.
我们的一份子
He was one of us.
难道他就白死了吗
Does that mean nothing?
那你为什么2-3月前不去找这些人算账
Why didn't you go after these guys two or three months ago?
因为我才调查清楚
Because I just found out about them.
要调查清楚又不难
What's to find out?
这事儿就发生在他们地盘上  对不对
It's a dispute over turf, right?
要在他们的地盘上找出凶手
I mean, how hard could it have been
对你来说能有多难
for you to track them down on their turf
你几月前早就能报仇了
and kill them months ago?
为什么没有报成呢
Because back then
因为当时你正忙于嗨药
you were too busy getting high,
忙于自怨自艾
feeling sorry.
但杀人
Now, murder...
绝不属于你那"改过自新12步"的范畴
is not part of your 12-step program.
杀人可不是你必须做的补偿
This is not some amends that you have to make.
所以你所说的毫无意义
What you are talking about here is pointless.
达不到任何目的
This achieves nothing.
你将一无所获
It accomplishes nothing.
如果你不理解个中利害关系
If you don't see what it accomplishes,
那我也没什么好解释的了
then there's no way I can explain it to you.
杰西  听我说
Jesse, listen to me.
你绝不是个杀人犯
You are not a murderer.
我不是  你也不是
I'm not, and you're not.
就是这样简单的道理
It's as simple as that.
杰西
Jesse...
不管有你没你  我都要去
I'm doing it... with or without you.
摊牌
Knock, knock.
老天爷  玛丽  要摊牌你得这样
Christ sakes, Marie, you don't say "Knock, knock."
-是敲出来的  -我喜欢说出来
- Like that. - Well, I like saying it.
规则可不是这样的  懂吗
Yeah, well, that's not the rules. Okay?
你摊你的  我摊我的
Listen, you knock your way, Groucho. I'll knock mine.
总之  看  我赢了
But, look, see? I win.
你高兴的太早了
Not so fast.
老天爷  你又赢了  三连胜了
Christ, again? That's three in a row.
保罗·纽曼灵魂附体
Frickin' Paul Newman over here?
你是不是常和你爸爸玩牌
Have you been playing cards with your dad?
不是  怎么了
No, why?
你老爸怎么样了
How is your old man?
他回去教书了没
He back teaching?
没有  我爸妈现在好像都没在工...
No, I don't think either of them are working right--
工作
right now.
是吗  怎么会这样
Yeah? How they swinging that?
知道吗  医生说你汉克姨父
Did you know that the doctor has told your uncle Hank
随时都可以出院
that he can get out of here any time he wants to.
真的吗  那太好了
Oh, yeah? That's great.
是的  可我们没准备好出院
Yeah, well, we're not so sure about that.
为什么
Why not?
怎么了  医生就是这么说的
What? That's what they said.
医生这么说是因为他们要用病房
That's what they said because they want the room.
给床单消消毒
They hit the sheets with Lysol,
重置下仪器  就可以又推个傻逼入院了
re-set the meter, and wheel the next slob in here.
玛丽  这事我们讨论过了  你放弃吧
We went over this, Marie. Drop it.
您身体还没恢复吗
Are you not well enough?
你也来烦我是吗
Jesus, kid, you, too?
你觉得我看上去好得很是吗
Do I look well enough?
我都快大小便失禁了
I'm shitting in pants, peeing in pitchers.
腿也动不了  懂了吗
Can't move my legs. Got it?
你是说坐轮椅的人都该住院吗
So people in wheelchairs should be in hospitals?
那拄拐杖的人呢
What about people on crutches?
看来我也应该住院才对
Maybe I should be in here, too.
您是这个意思吗
Is that what you're trying to say?
对  我就是这个意思
Yeah, that's exactly what I'm saying.
发牌  你个小混球
Deal, you little perk.
妈的
Bitch.
你知道我是按小时计费的吧
You know I'm hourly, right?
他答应过我他会来的
He promised me he'd be here.
噢  答应过  是吗  你早说啊
Oh, he promised, huh? Well, why didn't you tell me?
那我们慢慢等吧
Let's wait, then.
简直扯蛋  那小子不会来了
That's a joke. The kid ain't coming.
死心吧  你的二号方案是什么
Okay, so what's Plan B?
不知道
I don't know.
我真不知道
I really don't.
那就开动脑筋
Well, let's brainstorm.
你真的觉得他是来真的吗
You really think he's serious?
所以我才来这儿  索尔
That's why I'm here, Saul.
他和我说的时候那鼓劲  他真的会去做的
The way he was talking, he is going to do it.
或者至少会去试一试
Or try, at least.
好呀  那有什么  我们付给他钱呗
Okay, so, what, we pay him off.
不  不  不是钱的问题
No. No, it's not about money.
而是要想办法把他从街上拉回来
It's about getting him off the streets,
让他冷静下来
getting him to calm down.
要不然
Maybe--
如果我们...也许可以...
What if we... maybe--
你能不能找人把他抓起来
Could you get him arrested?
你
You--
你想把你的犯罪同伙送去警察局关起来
You want your criminal associate taken into police custody?
不是  听好
No, now, listen.
我知道这听起来很冒险
I know it sounds risky,
我说的那种"关起来"不是指
but it wouldn't be anything
那种真正的麻烦
that would get him into real trouble
而是那种不会牵涉到我们的"麻烦"
and nothing that could lead back to our business.
治他个轻罪
Just some minor offense.
平克曼蹲监狱  不靠谱吧
Pinkman in jail-- I don't know.
我在想象那情景  但
I'm picturing it and--
不  不是真进监狱
No, not in jail
而是"象征性"地进监狱
as in... "Jail" Jail.
我说的更像是那种
I'm talking about one of those situations
犯人穿着橘红色的囚衣
where you're in an orange jumpsuit
沿着高速公路捡垃圾
picking up litter along the highway.
这就是监狱
That's jail.
你说这个有点高端了
You're talking about a level-two joint.
只要能让他不上街找事  关个30天之类的
Something that keeps him off the street for, say, 30 days.
等他出来之后
Then by the time he gets out,
火气消了  大家就能和谐往前看了
tempers have cooled and hopefully we can move on.
拉兹威调教中心就挺清闲
Well, Roswell Correctional's pretty low impact.
要在以前  我会推荐斯普林格
In the past I've recommended Springer,
不过自打他们翻新浴室之后
but hearing chancy things about their bathrooms
接连发生偶发事件  所以...
since they renovated, so...
所以可以办到的  对吗
So it's possible, right?
可以  不过这属于套餐外的额外服务
Yeah, well, it falls under my premium-services package,
你得另付酬金
but you can afford that.
我会联络我的私家侦探
I'll call my P.I.
你知道该怎么做吗
You understand what you have to do?
绝不能有第二个人知道
You can never talk to anyone.
懂吗
Right?
是绝不能  懂吗
I mean, ever. Understand?
懂
Yeah.
这东西是我从网上找来的
I found this stuff on the Internet.
花了几天才弄到手
Takes days to kick in.
只要你不说出去
Just keep quiet,
这事儿就根本不会牵连到你
and this won't ever come back to you.
你干这个没问题的  对吧
You're okay with this, right?
就把它想成和你平常的工作一样
Just think of it like it's the same thing as always.
你不过是在递送汉堡
You're just delivering some hamburgers.
这可不是递送汉堡那么简单
It's not just delivering hamburgers.
嘿  你有个孩子
Hey, you got a kid.
对吧
Right?
他叫什么
What's his name?
帕特里克
Patrick.
想象一下如果这两个人
Imagine these two guys
把帕特里克当驴一样使
and Patrick working as a mule,
让他去杀人
making him kill people.
你难道不会站出来保护他吗
Wouldn't you do anything to protect your kid?
我当然会
Of course I would.
我愿意为他做任何事
I do all kinds of things for him.
好的  那么
Okay, so...
那些人这样利用孩子们
these guys using kids like that,
他们必须得死
they got to go.
对吧
Right?
很好
Good.
明天
Tomorrow.
咱们再联系
We'll be in touch.
这个一定很好吃  对吗
Bet that tastes good, huh?
来抱抱
Come here.
好样的  我们来觉觉
Okay, here we go.
睡觉觉啦
Here we go.
你来干什么
What are you doing?
如果你想谈  打电话
If you need to talk, use the phone.
电话上说不清楚  沃尔特
This isn't a phone talk, Walter.
你老婆出去了  对吧
Your wife's out, right?
她真是个小乖乖
Isn't she something?
我有一个孙女比她大点儿
I got a granddaughter a few years older.
你有何贵干
What can I do for you?
沃尔特  咱坐下说
Have a seat, Walter.
我跟古德曼谈过平克曼的事
I spoke to Goodman about Pinkman
还有你的计划
and this plan of yours.
然后呢
And?
我不打算去做
I'm not going to do it.
为什么
Why?
因为这么做太傻了
Because it's moronic.
索尔说你原来这么干过
Saul said you've done things like this before.
那部分不算傻
That's not the moronic part.
那么是什么问题
Okay, so what's the problem?
问题是老板可不会满意
The problem is the boss wouldn't like it.
索尔吗
Saul?
我的老板
My boss.
也是你的老板
Your boss.
我这次来  只是出于礼节
This is a professional courtesy.
没人知道我来过这儿  懂吗
No one knows I'm here. Understand?
但我们的老板会知道   一直是这样
But our employer would find out, like always,
而且如果平克曼被抓了
and if Pinkman were arrested,
他会把这事当成一个问题
he'd take it as a problem.
沃尔特  你现在的生活真的不错了
Walt, you got a good thing going here.
我们都是
We all do.
你想拿这一切去冒险救一个瘾君子吗
You want to risk it all on one junkie?
我知道你俩过去有交情
Now, I realize you two have a history,
但这小子现在已经很危险了
but this kid's been on the bubble a while now.
让我想起很久以前的事
It's a long time coming.
什么事
What is?
很久以前我曾是一名巡逻警察
I used to be a beat cop, long time ago,
我总被派去处理家庭纠纷
and I'd get called out on domestic disputes all the time.
那些年  加一起差不多数百起吧
Hundreds, probably, over the years.
但有这么一个人
But there was this one guy,
那个混蛋我永远都不会忘
this one piece of shit that I will never forget.
他叫戈迪  长得有点像博·史文森[橄榄球明星]
Gordie. He looked like Bo Svenson.
你记得那人吗
You remember him?
个子高高的  还记得吗
Walking Tall? You don't remember?
不记得算了  反正
No. Anyway...
大块头  270,280磅
big boy-- 270, 280,
他的妻子
but his wife--
或无论她是谁
or whatever she was--
他的女人吧  简直是小鸟依人
his lady was real small, like a bird,
小手腕细得跟树枝一样
wrists like little branches.
然后呢
Hmm. Anyway,
我和搭档每周末都会被叫去调解
my partner and I get called out there every weekend,
我们总会把她拉到一边  对她说
and one of us would pull her aside and we'd say,
振作起来  今晚我们就要对他正式起诉
"Come on, tonight's the night we press charges."
这不是那种
And this wasn't one of those
"在心底里他是爱我的"的老情节
"Deep down he really loves me" Set-ups.
我们碰到过很多  但这案子不是
We got a lot of those, but not this.
这女孩是真的很害怕
This girl was scared.
她拿他根本没办法
She wasn't going to cross him no way, no how.
我们能做的只是把她送去急救而已
Nothing we could do but pass her off to the EMTs,
把他叫上车  带到市区
put him in the car, drive him downtown,
把他扔到酒鬼拘押所
throw him in the drunk tank.
让他睡过去  到了第二天早上
He sleeps it off. Next morning,
照常回家
out he goes-- back home.
但有一晚
But one night
我搭档请了病假
my partner's out sick,
就我一个人
and it's just me.
电话又打来了
And the call comes in,
还是老戏码
and it's the usual crap--
说是"在浴室里摔倒弄破鼻子"之类的
broken-nose-in-the-shower kind of thing.
我就把他给拷上了  让他上车
So I cuff him, put him in the car,
把他带走了
and away we go.
只是那晚
Only that night...
我开车带他进市区
we're driving into town,
这混蛋
and this sideways asshole
坐在我的后座
is in my back seat
哼唱"男孩丹尼."
humming "Danny Boy."
我一下就火大了
And it just rubbed me wrong.
本来应该转左
So instead of left,
我却转右  把车开到了一个没人的地方
I go right, out into nowhere.
我让他跪下
And I kneel him down,
然后把枪塞到他嘴里
and I put my revolver in his mouth,
我告诉他
and I told him,
就是这样
"This is it.
你今天得死在这里
This is how it ends."
他吓哭了
And he's crying,
屎尿全都吓出来了
going to the bathroom all over himself,
对天发誓他再也不碰那女孩了
swearing to God he's going to leave her alone,
尖叫着
screaming...
因为枪还塞在他嘴里
as much as you can with a gun in your mouth.
我叫他安静
And I told him to be quiet...
因为我要好好想想接下来该怎么做
'cause I need to think about what I was gong to do here.
他当然安静下来了
And of course he got quiet.
就这样一直安静
Goes still.
真的很安静
And real quiet.
像条等剩饭的狗
Like a dog waiting for dinner scraps.
然后我们原地站了一会儿
Then we just stood there for a while.
我假装在考虑
Me acting like I'm thinking things over,
帅哥跪在泥里
and Prince Charming kneeling in the dirt
屁滚尿流
with shit in his pants.
几分钟之后
And after a few minutes
我把枪从他嘴里拔了出来
I took the gun out of his mouth,
对他说  "我发誓  你要是再敢碰她"
and I say, "So help me, if you ever touch her again,
"我就如此怎样怎样"
"I will such and such and such and such
"之类的那些话"
and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah."
只是警告一下他吗
Just a warning?
当然
Of course.
只是想要做件好事
Just trying to do the right thing.
可是两周之后  他杀了她
But two weeks later he killed her.
当然
Of course.
用搅拌机砸瘪了她的头
Caved her head in with the base of a Waring blender.
我们赶到的时候  到处都是血
We got there, there was so much blood,
空气里弥漫着铁锈的味道
you could taste the metal.
这个故事告诉我们一个道理
The moral of the story is...
我在本该决断的时候
I chose a half measure
采取了姑息折衷
when I should have gone all the way.
我绝不会再犯同样的错误
I'll never make that mistake again.
别再姑息折衷  沃尔特
No more half measures, Walter.
这是怎么回事
Man, I don't get this.
我搞不明白
I don't get this at all.
只看到那孩子
All I'm seeing is the kid.
他们到哪儿去了
So where are they?
我不知道
I don't know.
他们应该在附近的
They're always around.
汉堡都快凉了
Burgers are getting cold.
这东西  会很快吗
So is it, like, fast?
别慌  好吗  你只要一切如常就好
Don't sweat it, all right? You're just doing what you do.
没有人会知道
Nobody's going to know anything.
我能再喝一杯吗
Can I have another bump?
你已经喝过一杯了
You had your bump.
事成之后  你要什么都可以
We get this thing done. Then you can have all you want.
你得跟我走一趟
Going to need you to come with me.
你可以走了
Take a walk.
我们这是去哪儿
Where are we going?
坐下
Sit down.
我了解到你跟我的两名雇员之间有些矛盾
I understand that you have a problem with two of my employees.
他们确实杀死了你的一位合伙人
It is true that they killed one of your associates.
他们的行为可能有些鲁莽
It is possible they acted rashly,
但另一方面  他们也确实受到了挑衅
but, on the other hand, there was provocation.
有人在他们地盘上贩毒
A man was selling on their territory.
双方都有责任
There is blame on both sides.
此事到此为止
This will go no further.
就在此地  此刻解决
It will be settled right here, right now.
你告诉他了
You told him.
出去等
Wait outside.
你听好了
Listen to me.
这间屋子里  你只有一个朋友
You have one friend in this room.
就是这个人
This man.
外面那两个人
Those men outside
是我信任的雇员
are my trusted employees,
所以当我得知你打算...
and when I learned what you intended to do...
如果不是因为这个人
If it wasn't for this man
以及我对他的尊重
and the respect I have for him,
我会以完全不同的方式来处理你
I would be dealing with this in a very different way.
别看他  看着我
You don't look at him. You look at me.
接下来你该这样做
This is what happens now.
我的人进来以后
My men will come back inside,
你跟他们握手
and you will shake their hands
同他们和好
and you will make peace.
然后此事到此为止
And that will be the end of this.
不
No.
杰西
Jesse...
你说什么
Pardon me?
他们利用孩子
They use kids.
你手下这帮混蛋
These assholes of yours,
他们派一个11岁的孩子去帮他们杀人
they got an 11-year-old kid doing their killing for them.
我以为你是个通情达理的生意人
You're supposed to be some kind of reasonable businessman.
你就这样做生意的吗
This how you do business?
你不反对他们这样吗
You okay with this?
你不想说点什么吗
You got anything to say here?
叫他们进来
Bring them back.
不许再利用孩子
No more children.
懂了吗
Understand?
还有你
And you.
不许再闹了
You keep the peace.
说出来
Say it.
是  我不会再闹了
Yeah. I'll keep the peace.
握手
Shake hands.
杰西  你的行为
Jesse, your actions...
会影响到其他人
they affect other people.
有些时候
And sometimes
必须学会妥协
compromises have to be made...
理智一点
for the best of reasons.
别走  杰西  杰西
No, Jesse. Jesse!
玛丽  让那些拿了工钱的来干这活
Marie, let the people who get paid to do this, do this.
他们哪有我干的这么上心
The people who get paid to do this, do a lousy job.
这就是你想要的  对吧
So I guess this is what you want, huh?
躺在医院病床上
Just lying in a hospital bed,
让护士用海绵擦身
getting sponge baths from nurses.
玛丽
Marie.
该回家了  汉克
It's time to go home, Hank.
玛丽  还要我说多少次
How many times I got to tell you, Marie?
没痊愈我就不出院
Not till I'm well.
嘿  你干什么呢
Hey, what are you doing?
只是看看
I'm just seeing.
看什么
Seeing what?
你觉得我在看什么
Seeing what I see.
我现在状态不好  玛丽
I'm not at my best here, Marie.
我们走着瞧
We'll see.
不会有变化的
Nothing's going to happen.
我认为会的
I say it will.
我住院是有原因的
I'm in this bed for a reason.
你这是浪费时间
Well, it's a waste of time.
再说了  要是有人进来怎么办
Besides, what if someone comes in?
随便  我不介意有人进来
Let them. I don't care if someone walks in.
玛丽  你有毛病吗
Marie, what's wrong with you?
这样好了
I'll tell you what.
如果我能让你"重振雄风"的话...
If I can get the groundhog to see his shadow...
不可能的  抱歉
It's not going to happen. I'm sorry.
我打赌它会  如果我赢了
I'm betting it will, and if he does,
你就出院
you check out of here.
我才不和你赌这个
I'm not going to bet on whether I get a boner.
不赌  坚决不赌
It's not bet. There's no bet here. No bet.
你怕输吗
You afraid you'll lose?
你知道吗  这真是
You know what? You're just--
你又在犯傻了
You're just being foolish, you know?
拜托
Come on.
有意义吗
What's the point?
意义就是
The point is...
可以证明你并不是全无希望
you're not completely hopeless.
愿意赌了吗
We have a bet?
既然这样
You know what?
如果这能让你死心的话
If it'll get you out of here quicker,
给你一分钟
you got one minute.
一分钟吗
One minute?
好  那太简单了
All right. That's a cakewalk.
这真是
Yeah, this is just--
真是太悲哀了
It's just sad. I mean--
我真是同情你  你知道吗  玛丽
I really feel sorry for you, Marie, you know?
真的  这真是
I really do. It's just-- It's--
太可悲了
...pathetic.
没关系  随便你怎么说
That's okay. Keep talking.
抗议吧
Protest.
挣扎吧
Struggle.
玛丽  放弃吧
Marie, give up.
我是说真的  这
I mean, seriously, it's...
是
not...
不可能的事
going to happen.
今天过得很糟吗
Bad day?
我也不知道
I don't even know.
不过  现在好多了
Anyway, it's better now.
告诉他们你在忙
Tell them you're busy.
喂
Hello.
奶奶
Grandma?
慢点说
Slow down.
慢点  我听不清
Slow down. I can't--
什么
Oh, God.
天啊
我的天啊
Oh, God.
他在那里
There he is!
让我进去
Let me through.
托马斯
Tomas!
不
No!
让我进去  求你了
You have to let me in! Please!
是我  有事留言
Hey, it's me. Wait for the thing.
杰西  你迟到42分钟了
Jesse, you are now 42 minutes late.
我不等你了
I'm starting without you.
-什么是芥末酱  -芥末酱  回答正确
- What is wasabi? - Wasabi. Right you are.
我选"四字真言"  1200美元的奖励
"Four-letter Word" For 1,200.
飞行员和音乐家都知道这个词...
Pilots and musicians know this word...
晚饭快好了
Dinner's almost ready, okay?
-知道了  -凯文
- Okay. - Kevin.
-什么是"单干"  -回答正确
- What is "Solo"? - That's the word.
这人很厉害
This guy is good.
-我选"四字真言"  奖励是2000的词
- "Four-letter Word," 2,000. - "A loud"...
这词意为哭喊  沃尔特·惠特曼曾描述为"野蛮的"
harsh cry; Walt Whitman's was "Barbaric"
-是"叫喊"吧  -正确答案应该是"什么是嚎叫"
- Yell. - What is "Yawp"?
-凯文  -什么是"嚎叫"
- Kevin. - What is "Yawp"?
-"嚎叫"回答正确  -我选"东京"  奖励为1200
- "Yawp." - "Tokyo," 1,200.
到底什么是"嚎叫"  -一种甲壳纲动物...
What-- What the heck's a "Yawp"? - This crustacean...
"嚎叫"就是"叫喊"的一种
Uh, "Yawp" is a yell.
我离开一下
I'll be right back.
那是刚才我说的  -泰瑞
That's what I said. - Terry.
-"蟹"是什么  -不对
- What is crab? - No.
我能用下你的洗手间吗
Uh, okay to use your bathroom, right?
-我选"东京"  奖励是1600  -没问题
- "Tokyo" For 1,600. - Okay.
...是一种淡水蟹
...is the freshwater type.
是我  有事留言
Hey, it's me. Wait for the thing.
听着  你最好不是在生我的气
Look, I hope you're not waiting for an apology,
因为我没有出卖你
because I did not rat you out.
我百分之百坚持我的观点  并且
I was looking out for your best interest as well as my own,
我认为这是最好的解决方法
and I stand by my decision 100%,
求同存异也是允许的吧
so we'll just have to agree to disagree.
总之  给我回电话
Anyway, just call me back.
你以为电视会自己关掉吗
So the TV turns itself off, huh?
-是啊  -我来关
- Yeah. - Oh, I'll get it.
首先  让我们来关注一下今天的头条
But frist, more details on our top story
南谷的年轻男童谋杀案的后续报道
*******on the murder of a young boy in the South Valley.
警方尚未发表声明
Police have yet to release a statement,
但有消息指出
but sources indicate
昨晚有匿名人士向警方举报
that 11-year-old Tomas Cantillo
十一岁男童托马斯·坎蒂罗
may have been the victim of a gang-related execution.
在4700区第八大道的公园里
An anonymous tip brought police to a playground
惨遭帮派处决
on the 4700 block of 8th Avenue late last night.
医务人员随即赶到现场
Paramedics were called to the scene
但仍无法挽救男童
but were unable to revive the boy.
真是可怕的罪行
A gruesome crime,
能把电视关了吗
Can you turn that off?
这是自加强打击
...and yet another casualty in what appears to be
-城市毒品犯罪以来  -沃尔特
- the city's ongoing struggle - Walt?
发生的又一起黑帮贩毒而导致的惨案
against drugs and the gangs that peddle them.
我们会持续为您带来最新消息
We'll be passing along detail--
给你爸
Give your dad--
很抱歉
I'm sorry. It's just,
他们整天都在说这个  有点
they've been talking about that all day, and it's just...
是啊
Oh, yeah.
你知道我和你爸
Hey, uh, did you know your dad and I
在考虑打算合伙做生意吗
are thinking about maybe starting a business together?
真的吗
Seriously?
什么生意
What kind of business?
不知道
Um, I don't know.
可能开个洗车行吧
We're thinking maybe a car wash.
你是指  你以前打工的那种地方吗
What do you mean? Like the one you used to work in?
抱歉  我得走了
I'm sorry. I-- I have to go.
天啊
Oh, my God.
跑
Run.